

Gabriel Danaila

DEVELOPER SUPPORT ENGINEER / MECHATRONICS ENGINEER

gabriel.danaila.tech@gmail.com Tel: 0733.665.934 www.gabrieldanaila.com www.github.com/Gabriel-Danaila

WORK EXPERIENCE

Developer support Engineer for CGS in collaboration with Okta Customer Identity Cloud 2024 - Present

- Graduate Salesforce Commerce Cloud Developer training SFCC (feb 2024)
- · Knowledge of HTTP, encryption, basic security concepts.
- Understanding of authentication and authorization protocols.
- Completed Web Development Bootcamp by Dr. Angela Yu's (ian 2023) and WDS Bootcamp (sept. 2022).
- · Proficient in HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, VSCode.
- · Familiar with the React framework and TypeScript.
- · Create responsive designs using Figma and Visual Studio Code.
- · Manage version control using GitHub.
- Maintain a positive and collaborative environment with all team members.
- Stay update of the latest advancements and technologies in the field.
- Well-versed in web accessibility best practices and usability principles, continuously emphasising the importance of web best practices within the development team.
- With a strong background in troubleshooting and a natural inclination towards problem-solving, I leverage my expertise to address technical challenges promptly consistently ensuring the quality of my work.

Mechatronics Engineer - USA, TN

Feb 2007 - Feb 2019

Nissan - Battery Manufacturing Plant for Electric Vehicles, Smyrna , TN Leviton - Warehouse and Distribution center Facilities, Lebanon, TN Cinram - Assembly Line for Warner Bros Media , La Vergne, TN

- Proficiency in operating Mitsubishi and Yamaha industrial robots at the Nissan Battery Manufacturing Plant for Electric Vehicles
- Responsible for maintaining functionality of the equipment assigned using Omron Programmable Logic Controllers software and program backups for diagnostics and troubleshooting.
- Dedicated to resolving any silent faults using software diagnostic tools.
- Tested PLC changes with tools like LogicPro simulators and performed database additions for program backups, I/O operations, equipment function checks, and circuit change proposals.
- I've actively engaged in the adoption of concepts such as Kaizen implementation, Root Cause Analysis for major Breakdown Reports, Corrective - Preventive - Predictive Maintenance, the 5S methodology designed to foster a quality work environment - Sort, Set in Order, Shine, Standardise, Sustain.
- Architect of the Standard Operation Sheet Procedure (SOS), One Point Lessons for recurring tasks, standard steps and resource identification for efficient task execution.
- Completed training in safety protocols for Lock-out/Tag-out, power tools safety and general maintenance awareness.

HIGHLIGHTS

With 15 years of experience as a Mechatronics Engineer in the USA and three years as a Web Developer and Support Engineering for CGS.

I specialise in industrial programming of robots and PLC controllers, as well as in building reliable websites and applications using the latest technologies available.

Working on CGS provide me also with an expectations to become familiar with

Working on CGS provide me also with an opportunity to became familiar with security protocols, authentication and authorization concepts.

SKILLS

- HTML / ISML, CSS, JavaScript
- · Bootstrap, React, Node.js
- GitHub, Figma, Visual Studio Code
- · Robotics : software / hardware
- PLC Programming Omron controllers
- Programming Vision Systems, Scanners and Hmi
- Hardware verification and tests using software tools
- Strong mechanical / electrical troubleshooting skills
- Continuous learning and improvements

WORK RECOGNITIONS

- Emblem Plate Recognition for Work Ethics - Nissan 2013
- Best Employee Award 2012
- Perfect Attendance Award for 2011 / 2012

EDUCATION

Science Degree in Engineering (SIA) Technology and Quality Control. University of Galati , 1998 – 2004

- Prioritise work according to schedule and be ready to respond promptly to critical situations that could occur during the manufacturing process.
- Repair equipment using best practice available and follow up with team members for the current condition of the equipment during shifts changes
- Due to my strong work ethic and clean background, I quickly earn the trust
 of my team members, always prioritising safety as the number one concern
 in all activities.
- Drawing on my extensive experience, I significantly enhanced workflow
 efficiency for the battery cell assembly line by identifying bottleneck areas
 and optimizing the timing and speed of individual stages to minimize
 downtime.
- While working at Nissan North America, I was selected from a team of 50 maintenance technicians to participate in a battery training program in the United Kingdom in 2016. During this program, I collaborated with Japanese maintenance teams to install new assembly lines and implement a new battery process. Subsequently, I played a key role in adapting and applying these innovations at the Nissan Battery Plant in Smyrna, TN, USA.

TRAINING / CERTIFICATE

- · Okta security and Auth0 certificate
- · Salesforce Commerce Cloud Developer certificate
- · EVBP Mitsubishi and Yamaha Robotics programming and troubleshooting
- PLC Omron Programming (data types and network links)
- · Omron FZ3 Vision automated Vision systems
- ISO 50001/14001 EnMS General Awareness, Hazard Communication GHS
- RCA training Root cause analysis to identify potential risks, enabling proactive prevention or mitigation of problems before they arise
- Certified on Walkie rider, Order picker, Reach truck, Sit-down Lift, Scissor Lift
- · Power Tool Safety Level A,B,C,D
- · AMTEC Maintenance Skill Assessment
- · Safety protocols for Lock-out/Tag-out
- NFPA 70E 600 Volts or Less v2 training Arc Flash
- · CAMIC General Awareness Calibration / Measurement Instrument Control
- · American Red Cross Certificate CPR/AED, First Aid, Blood-borne Pathogens
- Hands-on training with Hitachi / Kyoto Japanese equipment, Dematic CL-100 and Sortech conveyors, Accusort Scanners, Hmi controllers

ABOUT ME

I value family time and show respect and care towards those around me. I strive to maintain a peaceful vibe in all interactions, always bearing in mind that, at our core, we journey through life together.

Recognised as an adaptable team player, I am always eager to learn and teach newly acquired skills.

REFERENCES

Gary Stinnett:

- Manager and Reliability Engineering at AESC (NIssan, Smyrna, TN)
- Tel: 615.414.7425
- gary.stinnett@nissan-usa.com

Tim Henderson:

- Technologist Engineering at AESC (NIssan, Smyrna, TN)
- Tel: 615.796.3185
- tim.henderson@nissan-usa.com

Jennifer Kauffman:

- Human Resources Specialist at Nissan Battery Plant, Smyrna, TN
- · Tel: 615.768.3686
- jennifer.kauffman@nissan-usa.com